Eduardo Brasileiro

409 Hanson Rd • Durham, NC 27713 (919) 744-6716 • epbrasil717@gmail.com

PROFESSIONAL OVERVIEW

Driven professional with experience handling critical projects and developing solutions. Strong ability to present and communicate complex topics to people of varied technical backgrounds. Direct use of analysis and visualization of large data to provide decision support to various industry representatives. Motivated and organized leader focused on meeting timelines and providing measurable results. Thought partner empowering media companies with data solutions.

TECHNICAL / PROFESSIONAL SKILLS

Programming Languages: Python, SQL, D3.js, Base SAS, SAS Macro, VBA, HTML

Software Packages: AWS, Microsoft Azure, Tableau, Git, SAS Visual Analytics, SAS Viya

Certifications: AWS Certified Machine Learning – Specialty

Microsoft Azure Data Scientist Associate

Microsoft Azure Fundamentals

DataCamp Data Scientist with Python Track

Languages: English, Portuguese, Spanish

EXPERIENCE

SAS INSTITUTE Cary, NC

Senior Pre-Sales Solutions Architect

August 2019 – Present

- Enable customers in Media and Telecommunications with innovative data solutions
- Integrate SAS with other technologies such as Python, SQL, and Cloud (Azure/AWS)
- Communicate demos, infrastructure, and solutions to stakeholders at all levels
- Design and develop high-impact automated dashboards in SAS Visual Analytics
- Work with teams to create proof of concept projects to show the art of the possible
- Media demos include contextual advertising (computer vision), ad forecasting (data pipelines and forecasting), end-to-end machine learning, open-source integration

SAS SOLUTIONS ONDEMAND ADVANCED ANALYTICS LAB

Cary, NC

Analytical Consultant

June 2015 – August 2019

- Guided over a dozen analysts in designing and implementing healthcare fraud solution
- Developed analytic code bases to enhance fraud detection in large amounts of noisy data
- Designed and implemented intuitive, interactive visualization for cluster rules in D3.js
- Integrated statistical models and SQL business rules to generate metrics for fraud detection
- Received OneSAS Award for proactive approach with escalated customer

GE ENERGY MANAGEMENT

Mebane, NC

Engineer

July 2013 - June 2014

- Created VBA programs to generate database documenting switchboard bill of materials
- Reported on results and managed expectations with management and designers
- Provided Microsoft Excel and VBA expertise to organize infrastructure of documentation

Eduardo Brasileiro, Page 2

EXPERIENCE continued

EPIC SYSTEMS Technical Services

Verona, WI January 2012 – July 2013

- Provided technical solutions for emergency departments (ED) across the country
- Used VBA to pioneer a project to generate Key Performance Indicators database and reports
- Taught Microsoft Excel macros class to groups of 20 to 30 from HR to developers
- Communicated with customers through weekly phone calls, emails, and on-site contact
- Used SQL to troubleshoot customer reports

EDUCATION

NORTH CAROLINA STATE UNIVERSITY, INSTITUTE FOR ADVANCED ANALYTICS May 2015

- Practicum: Developed multiple econometric stress testing models on M&T Bank's residential mortgage and home equity lines of credit portfolios for the Dodd-Frank Act Stress Tests and Comprehensive Capital Analysis and Review
- Practicum Team Lead: Organized technical team and established high level project vision to accomplish goals and deliverables discussed with M&T Bank liaison

NORTH CAROLINA STATE UNIVERSITY

Bachelor of Science in Applied Mathematics, summa cum laude **Bachelor of Science in Textile Engineering**, summa cum laude

Raleigh, NC December 2011 May 2011

- Valedictorian
- Minor Spanish

PERSONAL PROJECTS

MACHINE LEARNING FOR TENNIS (PYTHON/D3.JS)

- Created multiple predictive models for tennis grand slams in scikit-learn and TensorFlow
- Ensembled models achieved top 1% on tourneytopia for the 2019 Australian Open
- Engineered an interactive interface in HTML/CSS/JavaScript/D3.js
- Maintained code base in GitHub

NETFLIX'S PUNISHER TIME SERIES

- Scraped and analyzed tweets about the cancellation of The Punisher
- Used sentiment analysis to analyze what members thought of The Punisher Season 2

PROFESSIONAL DEVELOPMENT

COURSERA DATA VISUALIZATION WITH TABLEAU (UC DAVIS)

• Essential Design Principals, Creating Dashboards and Storytelling with Tableau

COURSERA RECOMMENDER SYSTEMS (University of Minnesota)

 Collaborative Filtering, Evaluation and Metrics, Matrix Factorization and Advanced Techniques